propertywide.co.uk 2019-04-03

# 

Countrywide Group Privacy Notice
The Countrywide privacy notice provides information on how Countrywide and any of its
subsidiaries, branches or representative offices and any 3rd party providers collect , use ,
secure, transfer and share your information. Countrywide Group and its affiliates
(Countrywide), is a leading provider of Residential development and consultancy practices,
Surveying Services, Conveyancing services, Corporate Property Services, Leasehold Estate
Management and Auctions. It operates in over 1,200 locations across more than 50 brands,
with over 11,000 employees within the UK.
     Countrywide has its head office at
     7th Floor
     UK House
     180 Oxford Street
     London
     W1D 1NN
It serves most major lenders, investors, house builders, commercial businesses,
corporations, local authorities, housing associations and the general public via the following
business units / divisions. Full details can be found on our website
http://www.countrywide.co.uk/about/
  Financial Services    This division includes the UK's largest single mortgage brokerage
                        and also offers expert advice on life and general insurance.
  Surveying             Countrywide Surveying Services (CSS) panel manage and
                        undertake valuations for the majority of UK mortgage lenders.
  Conveyancing          Countrywide Conveyancing Services (CCS) operates conveyancing
                        business, panel management and property lawyer firm in the UK,
                        offering: Sale and purchase (freehold and leasehold), Remortgage
                        and Separate legal representation.
  Asset                 Countrywide Corporate Property Services (CCPS) offer services in
  Management            the disposal of residential property assets to corporate clients in the
                        following sectors: Repossession asset management, Part exchange
                        sale, Corporate property sales and In-house maintenance services.
  Property              Countrywide Estate Management (CEM) specialises in property
  Management            management, providing leasehold and estate management services.
  Residential           This division is the UK’s largest land & new homes agency and offers
  Development           services to new buyers, national land opportunities and dedicated
                        new homes property lawyers.
                                           Page 1 of 10

 Property Auctions    This division uses the largest estate agency network for property
                      auctions
 Marketing            Markets Countrywide services via a suite of websites and other
                      means
 Retail               Sales and lettings service
 Relocations          Countrywide Relocation Solutions (CRS) offers a comprehensive
                      facilitation service providing pre-funded temporary accommodation
                      across the UK.
1. Types of Information Collected.
Typically Countrywide collect:
 1. First Name           21. How many              41. Personal /Secure     61. IP Address
                              Dependants                Loan Details
 2. Middle Name          22. Dependants            42. Personal Debt        62. Cookies
                              Name                      Details
 3. Surname              23. Dependants DOB        43. Personal             63. Marital Status
                                                        Expenditure
 4. Previous Name        24. Primary ID *          44. Existing             64. Salary
                                                        Mortgage Details
 5. Date of birth        25. Address ID *          45. Existing             65. Accountant
                                                        Insurance Details       Details
 6. Present Address      26. Bank Statements       46. Email Address        66. Previous
                              *                                                 employers
                                                                                details
  7. Residential         27. Credit Card           47. Phone Numbers        67. Employers
     Status                   Statements *                                      Address
 8. Previous             28. Mortgage              48. New Property         68. Employers
     Addresses                Statements *              Details                 Phone number
 9. Landlord Details     29. Proof of Deposit      49. Solicitor Details    69. Health
 10. Nationality         30. Payslips *            50. Estate Agent         70. Ethnicity
                                                        Details
 11. NI Number            31. Self Employed        51. New Mortgage         71. Credit Card
                              Accounts *                Details                 Details
 12. UK National         32. Employers Name        52. New Insurance        72. Bank Details
                                                        Details
 13. Doctors Details     33. Gender                53. Criminal Offences
                                                        /Convictions
*Copies
1.1. Methods of Collection
In the general conduct of business, Countrywide collects information relevant to the services
being sought across the range of services it offers (listed previously) from:
•   yourself
•   next of kin
                                         Page 2 of 10

•    spouse / partner / family member
•    business associates
•    Employers
•    “trusted” sources including:
         • Government / Land / Police registers
         • Credit / Default Agencies
         • Financial Institutes (Banks, Building Societies, Loan Agencies, Credit Card
             companies)
         • Insurance Companies
         • Other Law firms
         • Health providers
         • through consent to third parties disclosing information about you to us that they
             have collected
Such information will generally be collected directly via the use of any of our standard forms,
over the internet, via email, in our branches or through a telephone conversation with you.
We may also collect personal information through our affiliates or suppliers.
 In addition, you may choose to submit information directly to us via several methods,
including:
         •   through Countrywide and affiliates websites
         •   in response to marketing or other communications
         •   through social media
         •   by signing up for a Countrywide product or service
         •   through participation in an offer, program or promotion
         •   in connection with an actual or potential business or employment relationship
              with us
You may also agree to third parties disclosing information about you to us that those third
parties have collected.
We, our service providers and partners collect certain information by using automated
means, such as cookies and web beacons, when you interact with our advertisements,
mobile applications, or visit our websites, pages or other digital assets. The information we
collect in this manner may include: IP address, browser type, operating system, referring
URLs and information on actions taken or interaction with our digital assets.
We may use third-party web analytics services on our websites and mobile apps The
analytics providers that administer these services use technologies such as cookies and web
beacons to help us analyse how visitors use our websites and apps.
"Your Rights and Choices" section of this Privacy Notice specifies your ability, to opt out or
limit the usage of the information collected.
1.2. Purposes of Collection
Generally, we will collect, use and hold your information for the purposes of:
   • Assessing applications for and providing Countrywide products / services
   • Conducting business, developing relationships with Countrywide and affiliates
                                          Page 3 of 10

           •   Process payments / transactions including: Accounting, Authorisation,
               Clearing, Chargebacks, Auditing, Billing, Reconciliation, Collection,
               Complaints, Enquiries, Credit Checks and related dispute resolution activities
    •  Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorised transactions, money laundering
       (please see below), tax evasion, claims, other liabilities and manage risk exposure and
       agent /franchise quality, integrity, compliance and security of business processes
    •  Create and manage any accounts, associated authentication criteria (id’s and
       passwords) you may have with Countrywide
    •  Provide, administer and communicate with you about Countrywide products, services,
       offers, programs and promotions, their issuers, acquirers, retailers and partners.
    •  Compile business directories, including business contact information
    •  Operate, monitor, evaluate and improve our products, services, websites, mobile
       applications, other digital assets and business.
           • Developing new products and services
           • Managing communications, assess effectiveness and optimisation of
               advertising
           • Functionality of our websites, mobile applications other digital assets
    •  Evaluate your interest in employment and contact you regarding possible employment
       opportunities
    •  Enforce Countrywide “Terms of Use”, other legal rights as may be required by
       applicable laws and regulations or requested by any judicial process or governmental
       agency having or claiming jurisdiction over Countrywide or its affiliates.
    •  Comply with industry standards and Countrywide policies
Anti-Money Laundering
In addition to help you with a property related service we have to comply with certain
regulations for example the “Money Laundering, Terrorist Financing and Transfer of Funds
(Information on the Payer) Regulations 2017 (referred to as “the Regulations).” Countrywide
Estate Agents (CEA) and other subsidiaries are required to obtain certain information from
you to comply with regulations. The information provided will only be used by Countrywide
Plc in relation to complying with the Regulations and will not be shared with any other party
outside of the companies wholly owned by Countrywide Plc unless we are required to do so
under law.
If you decide to enter in to a business relationship with Countrywide Estate Agents or any
wholly owned subsidiary to comply with certain regulations.
We will require two separate Identification documents one primary and one secondary
document even if it appears on both lists. The information may be required at various stages
of the process depending whether you are:
Purchasing (or Selling)
         Primary documents - proof of ID
             •     Valid Passport with MRZ
             •     Valid full UK photo driving licence
             •     Valid full UK Driving licence (Non photo, paper) issued before 1998
             •     Valid EU/EEA/Switzerland photo driving licence.
             •     Valid EU/EEA/Switzerland national Identity Card.
             •     Valid UK Armed Forces ID Card.
             •     Valid UK Biometric Residence Permit (copy of both sides.)
             •     Valid Blue disabled drivers pass. (With photo)
             •     Valid Freedom Pass
             •     Valid Local Authority Bus pass.
                                            Page 4 of 10

            •        Department for Works & Pensions letter confirming pension details
                 including National Insurance Number dated within the last 12 months.
           Secondary documents - proof of residence (home.)
            •        Valid full UK photo driving licence.
            •        Valid full UK Driving licence (Non photo, paper) issued before 1998
            •        Local authority council tax bill (dated within the last 12 months).
            •        UK Bank / Building societies statements/bills showing activity, dated within
                 the last six mths. Including account number and sort code. (Internet printed
                 acceptable.)
            •        UK mortgage statement (dated within the last 12 months.) (Internet printed
                 acceptable.)
            •        Utility bill dated within the last 6 months including - Electricity bill (with
                 MPAN number), Landline, Gas, Satellite TV, Water. (Internet printed
                 acceptable.) (Not mobile phone bills.)
            •        Her Majesty’s Revenue and Customs (HMRC) Inland Revenue (IR) Coding
                  / assessment / statement (dated within the last 12 months) with National
                 Insurance number.
            •        Department for Works & Pensions letter confirming pension details and NI
                 Number. (Dated within the last 12 months).
We reserve the right to employ third party electronic verification for the purpose of verifying
identity. This search will not affect your credit rating
1.3. Lawful basis of processing
Countrywide processes your information under the following
    •   Performance of a contract: where you enter into a contract with Countrywide and we
        need to process your information as part of this contract
    •   Legitimate interests: some information is processed by Countrywide as part of its
        legitimate interests which include :Fraud, risk assessment, due diligence, network
        and information security, suppressions and managing opting out of communications ,
        profiling , direct marketing, monitoring, web analytics, cloud storage, acquisitions,
        updating customer details, lettings, sales, financial services and other core products
        and service provided by the data controller
    •   Public interest: some information is processed in accordance public interest such as
        relocations
    •   Consent : where we process information under consent we will seek you clear and
        unambiguous consent prior to processing your data
2. Information We Share
We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information we collect about you, except as
described in this Privacy Notice or as indicated via the consent process at the time the data
is collected. We share the information we collect with, but not limited to:
•   Landlords and landlord associates and sub processors
                                               Page 5 of 10

•    Vetted affiliates and partners / Financial Institutions / Insurance Companies for business
     facilitation to provide required services, such as mortgages, insurance cover etc.
•    Formally contracted service providers to perform services on our behalf:
     • Hosting Datacentres, Infrastructure, Applications (Development / Support) , Cloud
         Services (Software as a Service – SaaS, Platform as a Service – PaaS ,
         Infrastructure as a Service – IaaS)
      • Helpdesk, Call Centres etc.
         We contractually require these service providers to safeguard the privacy and
         security of personal information they process on our behalf and authorise them to
         use or disclose the information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf
         or comply with legal requirements
•    Councils, health and care providers
•    Other Law firms
•    Credit agencies, Land Registry Office, Her Majesty’s Revenue and Customs (HMRC),
     Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) and other relevant regulatory bodies
•    Additionally we may share information about you, if required legally, to prevent harm or
     financial / reputation loss, for investigation of suspected or actual fraudulent or illegal
     activities.
•    Perspective employers requesting references via your written consent
On websites, features can be accessed where we partner with other entities that are not
affiliated with Countrywide. These include social networking, geo-location tools etc. are
operated by third parties (indicated appropriately) who may use or share personal
information in accordance with their own privacy policies. It is recommended that you review
the third parties' privacy policies if you use the relevant features.
Countrywide reserve the right to transfer your information in the event of a sale or transfer
(wholly or partially) of our business or assets, with reasonable efforts for the acquirer protect
/ use your information consistent with our Global Privacy Notice. You can exercise your
rights to contact the acquiring entity with questions concerning the protection and processing
of your information.
2.1 How long do we keep information for
We will keep information for a reasonable amount of time in order to perform the purposes
listed above.
We only keep your information for as long as necessary. We generally keep personal
information for 7 years after last contact with you. However Countrywide reserves the right to
keep information for longer if we feel that this is in the legitimate interests of Countrywide.
2.2 International Data Transfers
Countrywide may transfer the personal information collected about you to recipients in
countries other than the country in which the information was originally collected. Those
countries may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially
provided the information. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will
                                             Page 6 of 10

protect that information as described in this Privacy Notice or as otherwise disclosed to you
at the time the data is collected (e.g. via program specific privacy notice).
We currently engage a company called WNS who are based in India. We have ensured that
WNS meet the required privacy and security requirements through our contract with WNS.
You can find out more about WNS here http://www.wns.com/
2.3 Profiling
For the purposes of business conduct, enhancement, identification of fraud, money
laundering and other potential un-authorised activities, Countrywide engages profiling
activities via direct use or anonymisation of sensitive personal information.
          2.3.1 Direct Profiling
          Direct profiling is engaged for the fair and lawful purposes, to provide Countrywide
          the ability to enforce Countrywide “Terms of Use”, legal reporting as may be
          required by applicable laws, regulations, policies / standards or requested by any
          judicial process or governmental agency having or claiming jurisdiction over
          Countrywide or its affiliates; including, but not limited to:
          •   Benchmarking employees: appraisals, performance, bonus payments,
              disciplinary actions, improvement plans, promotions and awards.
          •   Background checks for existing and new employees, clients, business partners,
              affiliates
          •   Financial Viability analysis / reports
          •   Business partner / client portfolio position, performance, risk positions
          •   Anti-money laundering
          •   Tax reporting
          •   Credit defaulting / exposure
          2.3.2 Indirect Profiling
          Indirect profiling via anonymisation of personal information is also used for
          preparing and furnishing aggregated data reports showing anonymised information,
          including, but not limited to, the following:
          • Compilations, analyses, analytical and predictive models and rules, and other
               aggregated reports for the purpose of advising our partners / affiliates and
               servicing institutions, retailers and other customers regarding past and potential
               future patterns of service usage, spending, fraud, and other insights that may be
               extracted from this data.
          • Compiling and communicating promotional and marketing information about
               products and services that Countrywide Group, affiliates and other organisations
               that we have affiliations with have and that may be of interest to you.
          • Conducting market research
          • Facilitating our internal business operations, including the fulfilment of any legal
               requirements.
2.4 Your Rights and Choices
Your rights regarding the sensitive / personal information we maintain about you enable you
to exercise choices about what personal information we collect from you, how we use that
information, and how we communicate with you.
                                             Page 7 of 10

Please completed the web form here subject access request form
If you have any problems completing this form please use contact details below
2.5 Access and Correction
You may have the right to:
•   obtain confirmation that we hold personal information about you
•   request access to and receive information about the personal information we maintain
     about you
•   receive copies of the personal information we maintain about you
The right to access personal information may be limited in some circumstances by local law
requirements.
To exercise these rights, please contact us as set forth below.
2.6 Update and correct inaccuracies in your personal information
If you feel that the information we hold about you in incorrect or inaccurate you can contact
us outlining the information you feel is incorrect of inaccurate
If we refuse to correct your personal information, we will provide you with a written notice
that sets out the reasons for our refusal (unless it would be unreasonable to provide those
reasons) and provide you with a statement regarding the mechanisms available to you to
make a complaint. We will provide you with access to information we hold about you:
2.7 Object to the processing of your personal information
If you would like to object to any processing of your information by Countrywide you can
contact us outlining what processing of information you would like to object to.
2.8 Have the information blocked, anonymised or deleted
If you would like countrywide to delete, block or anonymise information we hold about you,
you can contact us outlining what information you would like deleted , blocked or
anonymised.
To update your preferences, ask us to remove your information from our mailing lists or
submit a request to access, update, correct or delete your personal information, please
contact us as specified in the “How To Contact Us” section below.
2.9 Opting out of processing
You can opt out collection of personal information by automated means e.g. when visiting
our website or visit third-party websites and interact with our adverts, by using the Cookie
Consent tool displayed in the website (the browser you use may provide options on how to
opt out of receiving certain types of cookies). However without cookies you may not be able
to use all of the website features and/or online services.
                                          Page 8 of 10

Countrywide operate a cookie policy. Some of our service providers and partners may collect
information about your online activities over time and across third-party websites to
customise and target our adverts.
You can at any time tell us not to send you marketing communications by
•   e-mail privacy@countrywide.co.uk
•   unsubscribing via the “unsubscribe link” within the marketing e-mails you receive from
     us, or
•   contacting Countrywide as indicated below.
2.10 Withdrawal of consent
If we obtain your information by consent you have the right to withdraw any consent you
previously provided to us.
If we process your information under legitimate interest you can object at any time on
legitimate grounds, to the processing of your personal information.
Countrywide we will apply your preferences going forward. Doing so will mean that you
cannot take advantage of certain Countrywide and affiliate products, services and
promotions.
The right to consent removal may be limited in some circumstances by local law
requirements and you will be informed appropriately.
3    How to Contact Us / Complaints and Feedback
If you:
•   make a complaint about a breach of your personal information, applicable privacy laws /
     principles or a concern about Countrywide privacy practices
•   would like access and/or update information or preferences you provided to us,
You also may e-mail us at:
privacy@countrywide.co.uk
Or write to us at:
Carly Hitchman Data Protection Officer
Countrywide House
88-103 Caldecotte Lake Drive
Caldecotte Lake Business Park
Caldecotte
Milton Keynes
MK7 8JT
                                         Page 9 of 10

If we fall short of your expectations in processing your personal information or you wish to
make a complaint about our privacy practices, please contact us via the details in the "How
To Contact Us" section below.
To assist us in responding to your request, please give full details of the issue. We attempt
to review and respond to all complaints within a reasonable time.
If we cannot for lawful reasons complete your request we will explain this to you to the extent
that we lawfully can.
3.1 How We Protect Personal Information
The security of your personal information is very important and Countrywide is committed to
protecting the information we collect. We maintain administrative, technical and physical
safeguards designed to protect the personal information you provide or we collect against
accidental, unlawful or unauthorised destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use.
We use SSL encryption on a number of our websites from which we transfer certain
personal information.
Countrywide stores personal information only for as long as it is necessary for the fulfilment
of the purpose for which the personal information was collected, unless otherwise required
or authorised by applicable law. We take measures to destroy or permanently de-identify
personal information if required by law or if the personal information is no longer required for
the purpose for which we collected it.
4   Updating this privacy statement
We will update this statement from time to time so we suggest that you review this statement
at regular intervals. Where we undergo substantial changes to our privacy statement we will
endeavour to inform you directly about these changes.
July 2018
                                          Page 10 of 10
